Okay. Um, it is time to install Git. So,
the way you install Git is you I'm going
to have you search for Git.
Um, and then it's going to be this, um,
git-scm.com.
Uh, you can see it here that goes
directly to downloads, but I'm going to
take you to the homepage. So, here on
the homepage, it will probably figure
out um what type of device you're on
automatically and give you the download.
Um, alternatively, you can go to
downloads and click on Windows. Here,
um,
it it says click here to download the
latest installer. This is for a 64-bit
Windows. Um, if you are running Windows
11, that is the only type of Windows. If
you are running Windows 10 or older, um,
you can come here to check. You would
click on the start menu, then click on
settings, and then system, and then
about, and then you'd open about. And
then you'd look next to device
specifications and then it'll list
whether or not you have a 32-bit or
64-bit Windows. Chances are high you
have a 64-bit Windows. Um so
um I'm going to down click here to
download the latest version. And it's
going to download an installer. And I've
actually pre-downloaded this installer.
So I'm going to click on that installer.
Um sorry. Okay, let me grab this window
and bring it in.
All right, so um you'll want to open up
the installer and
it's going to probably ask you if you
want it to make changes to your device.
You're going to click yes
and I'm going to pause the video while
this loads.
Never mind. I didn't even get the video
paused before it loaded. Okay. Um, there
is going to be this license that you
have to agree to. So, I'm going to hit
next. And then it's going to ask what
you want installed. And I'm just going
to leave everything as default and hit
next. And then it says, do you want to
use Vim? Um, go ahead and hit next. And
then we'll go ahead and
we're going to just uh we're going to
click override the default branch for
new repositories. And so it's going to
make the default branch main. Um there
was some negative connotation
surrounding the word master. Um so the
old version of git would use the word
master, but we're going to go ahead and
overwrite it and click main. And we're
going to hit next. Um
use it from the command line third party
software. We're just going to hit next.
Um, we're going to hit next. We're going
to hit next. Going to hit next. And hit
next. And hit next. And hit next. And
then we're going to hit install. And
then I'm going to pause this until it's
done installing.
Okay. So, it is now finished. Um, so you
can view the release notes if you want.
I don't really want it. So, I'm going to
hit finish. Okay. What I want you to do
now is I want you to type terminal and
you're going to look for an open
PowerShell.
Okay. When this opens, you're going to
type get. And if you can type get and it
gives you a whole bunch of stuff here,
then you have successfully installed
get. Once you have done that, um, you
are going to want to run a few lines on
your terminal. The first one you're
going to want to run is you're going to
want to type get
config-
global
and then user.name.
And then you're going to want to put in
your username. Um, this is what's going
to show up on your requests to make
edits. So I'm going to put to
get config
global user.
And this is where you're going to want
to put the email that you have
associated with GitHub. So in my case
it's to teaches tech.gmail.com
and then I'll hit enter. And now I've
successfully configured that. Once you
are done you have successfully installed
git and you are good to go. Just some
caveats here. If you open up Visual
Studio Code and you had a terminal
running, you might run git and it might
say it's not recognized. So, what you'll
want to do is you want to kill that
terminal and then come up here and click
terminal, new terminal. And that will
open the terminal. And then you should
be able to type get and it should run um
now that your terminal has been
refreshed. All right, that covers how
you install Git on a Windows. Thanks for
watching.